♫ In the not too distant future
♫ Somewhere in time and space
♫ Mike Nelson and his robot pals
♫ Are caught in an endless chase
♫ Pursued by a woman
♫ Whose name is Pearl
♫ An evil gal who want to rule the world
♫ She threw a few things in her purse
♫ And in her rocket ship
♫ She hunts him all across the universe ♫
- [Voiceover] I'll get you.
♫ I'll send him cheesy movies
♫ The worst I can find
♫ La la la
♫ He'll have to sit and watch them all
♫ And I'll monitor his mind
♫ Now keep in mind
♫ Mike can't control
♫ When the movies begin or end
♫ He'll try to keep his sanity
♫ With the help of his robot friends ♫
- [Voiceover] Robot roll call.
Cambot.
- You're on.
- [Voiceover] Gypsy.
Tom Servo.
- Check me out.
- [Voiceover] Croooow.
♫ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes
♫ And other science facts
♫ Just repeat to yourself
♫ It's just a show
♫ I should really just relax
♫ Oh Mystery Science Theatre 3000 ♫
- Hi everyone welcome to
the satellite of love here.
- Hi.
- Probably wondering
what's up with Crow here.
Well I'll let him explain.
Go ahead.
- Explain what?
Oh yeah, the nest.
Um.
Yeah it turns out that the top of my head
provides a perfect
nesting site for the rare
Spix's macaw.
I've known that for some time,
but this is the first time I've had
an actual brooding mother.
- See what I don't get is
how you cannot notice them
building a nest on the top or your head.
- Well I was aware of some activity Mike.
But you know it's the top of my head.
I suppose you know every
detail at all times
of everything happening
at the top of your head?
- I guess not.
- Yeah.
- When does that one hatch anyway?
- Ah well pretty soon Mike.
It's been three weeks
and to tell you the truth
I'll be a little relieved.
The Spix's macaw is not a small bird.
So when the mother's actually here,
sitting on my head with that brooding spot
all pink and warm.
There's no feathers, it just,
whoa whoa.
Here she comes again.
(swaucking)
Damn another one.
- Great.
We'll be right back.
- Mike would you mind doing this one.
I feel like I've done my
part for the Spix's macaw.
- Well you're the one with
the perfect nesting site head.
- [Voiceover] Ack.
Get away your rebel.
Cease and assist.
Back I say.
Okay then you mongrels.
(gun shots)
(laughing)
Eat it.
- Uh, Crow.
Every thing alright?
- Oh yeah I had a little
weasel problem there Mike.
They were trying to steal
my poor little eggs.
I never knew weasels
could be such weasels.
- Pearl's goons are calling.
Yellow.
- What, do you want a little more?
- No.
- Alright Sporto.
This time you are one dead monkey.
One, two, three.
(grunts)
Oh god.
Alright, best out of 99 then.
(laughing)
- Oh hello disturbingly unhairy ones.
The lovely Pearl still gone.
- Yay!
- Wee, woo hoo!
- Yes.
- Oh yeah, that's a shame.
- Dog gonnit.
- Really.
- But stay tuned for this
important message from her.
Okay rubber arms, back to work.
- Yes.
Accessing satellite relay to Los Angeles.
Come in Pearl.
Pearl, come in.
Pearl, come in, can you read me.
- Calm down brainiac.
Yeah hi everyone.
I flew the van out here to LA
to try and find some more movies
to torture you guys with.
Thought I'd consult an expert.
So I took and went and
gone and got this guy here,
from Entertainment Tonight.
- Hello Mike.
Hello small robots.
How can I help?
- Leonard Maltin.
Pearl you are connected, woo.
- Excuse me Mister Maltin,
what do you make of these
stylistic resurgence
of Italian neo-realist film making
in the vain of De Sica's Umberto D?
- Yeah, Maltin.
Is it true their working
on yet another remake
of The Fish that Saved Pittsburgh?
- Oh yeah yeah.
- Stop bugging Mister
Siskel with questions.
- Maltin.
- He's helping me.
So what do you recommend Roger?
- Leonard.
I'd highly recommend the
1961 monster movie, Gorgo.
It's sort of a British
take on the godzilla thing.
- Uh, Mister Maltin,
is Gorgo really that bad?
I mean, you're not really
gonna hurt us, are ya?
- Well that's a matter of opinion Mike.
Now I actually like Gorgo.
But when we reviewed it for my number one
best selling video and movie guide,
it put two of my assistant
editors into intensive care.
So who knows?
Besides, Pearl promised me
a light lunch at Skybar.
- No.
I said one appetizer only, Ebert.
- Maltin.
- Okay Mister Maltin Ebert.
Don't push you luck or it's
a small decaf at Starbucks.
- Well.
- Brainguy.
- Oh oh yes Pearl?
Do you mind?
- Please, not at all.
- Okay.
And go.
- Hey Crow your eggs are gone.
- Oh yeah, they got taken away
by egg protective services.
I accidentally made an
omelet in front of them.
Kinda spooked them.
- Yeah well I hope you get to visit.
(Beeps)
- Oh movie's on.
- Mister Maltin!
(instrumental music)
- Wow.
- Right down here.
(mumbling)
- London, England.
Yeah which is paid for by exorbident taxes
on Rod Stewart and Pete Townsend.
- Wait I just got three words into it.
- What a terrible name for a movie.
- The vice president's
unimaginative campaign slogan.
- Good masonry work on the titles.
- Yeah it was done by the guys
at Mark Seven Productions.
- Aw.
♫ Oh Gorgo boy, the
gore, the gore is goring
♫ From gore to gore
(snickers)
- Fa young loves Fa young.
- You know, name your kid Muir Mathieson,
he's pretty much destined to
conduct the Sinfonia of London.
- The lost stooge.
- Yeah yeah and all these other goons
from the septered isle.
♫ Down with the old folks at home ♫
- Who's Paul Robison?
Lovely.
- Hawii 5-0 use to have
really different credits.
- Frank King, Maurice King.
- Administration.
- Did Frank sneak in afterwards
and put that little dig
under Maurice's name?
- I think that ships PC
valve is a little off there.
- Without a hard tack.
- Poop Deck Pappy, the real story.
- Sam, it's looking terrible ugly.
- [Tom Servo] Well thanks a lot.
- The men are getting edgy.
- Yeah, so am I.
- [Crow] Need any freelance
frog matting services?
- [Voicoever] Come on Joe,
make it snappy will ya?
Come on, let's get outta here.
- Now wait a minute Sam.
There's thousands of
dollars worth of stuff
in that old rust bucket.
I'm not getting outta here without it.
- Are you kiddin'?
- [Tom Servo] We have to
go find Robert Denbey.
- [Voiceover] Stop worrying.
I'll stake it out and be
back up in 10 minutes.
- [Crow] I should moisturize.
(snickering)
- [Mike] I think the
pool guy over chlorinated
the ocean here.
- [Tom Servo] Oh, this
new cool ranch flavored
scuba air isn't very good.
- [Crow] The legendary lost
treasure of Captain Crunch.
- [Tom Servo] Oh look, he carries his own
little expresso machine
on his back with him.
- [Crow] Somebody's got to get
on the other side of that boat
or we're in trouble guys.
- [Voiceover] He's been down half an hour.
- I know these waters well Sam.
I've never seen the like of this before.
- [Mike] Just puts my hate out of shape.
- Get me a lung.
I'm going down to get him.
He's come up.
- [Tom Servo] I put the
propane tanks on by mistake.
- [Crow] It's Robert Maxwell, he's alive.
- [Tom Servo] Aah.
- [Voicevoer] Move it forward Derek.
- [Mike] Our game of Risk.
- [Crow] Ah Mike, Servo,
for what it's worth.
My heart will go on.
- [Mike] Good.
- [Crow] Okay.
(chuckling)
- [Mike] You know when
this boat was launched,
it was promoted as pretty damn sinkable.
- [Servo] The HMS over-easy.
- [Crow] Yeah it's rough.
But is it really too rough to feed us?
- [Mike] I'm drowning and I'm wet.
- [Servo] Gary I'm steering.
- [Mike] Great, now our
toothpick sculpture.
- [Servo] Let go.
- [Mike] Man, this is worse than when
Australia formed right next to us.
- [Crow] Don't worry sir,
turns out Shelly Winters
is a very good swimmer.
- [Mike] And?
Oh they're fine.
(laughing)
♫ They got him to port
♫ And everyone was okay
♫ They went out for
lunch and felt better ♫
- [Servo] Hey, Mike Nelson.
- [Mike] Hey, Tom Servo.
- [Servo] No, I mean.
Nevermind.
Dummy.
- [Mike] Why?
Well I'm sure it's fine.
I don't know much about propellers anyway.
- [Servo] I guess I shouldn't have thrown
the captain's hat overboard.
He wasn't pleased.
- [Crow] Well there's
water in the basement.
Carpets all ruined.
- Not as bad as I thought Joe.
- [Voiceover] How long
to get her into shape.
- Ruter starks bent,
couple of sprung plates.
- [Voiceover] Uh huh.
- At best on deck, three or four days.
- And we're out of fresh water.
- [Mike] We'll have to
drink concentrate then.
- Let's go on shore and
see what they got, eh Sam?
- [Servo] Yes, let's put on
some Old Spice and go ashore.
(whistling)
- [Crow] There's dead cows in the water.
- Look there.
- [Servo] A tuna swallowed an armadillo.
- I've never seen
anything like that before.
- [Mike] Some kind of
sealecanth death cult
or something, I don't know.
- [Servo] Let's sell it to the Japanese
for 60,000 dollars.
- The whole ocean bottom
must of been torn up.
- [Crow] Ick, can I wipe
on your jacket please.
(bell ringing)
- [Mike] Wow, new island
got settled very quickly.
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Servo] Lice for sale.
Chiggers and lice.
- Looks like they were pretty hard hit.
- Yeah.
- [Mike] Poor dopes.
They appear every hundred years
and get hit by a huge storm.
- Hi, is there a harbor
master we can talk to?
- [Servo] Something about a kinnish.
- Gaelic, huh?
- Didn't sound like
welcome in any language.
- [Crow] So how do you get
your shirt so white, Shamus?
- [Mike] Say quiet man.
- Hey kid, is your father at home?
- I don't have a father.
- Oh.
Does the harbor master live here?
- It's the right place
you've come to then.
Come in.
- [Servo] Did you see me
in How Green was my Valley?
- [Crow] Me mum's at work,
so I'm having a garage
sale with her stuff.
- You say the harbor master lives here?
- Yes, a city man he is.
A government man.
- Who is he?
What's he do?
- McCartin's his name.
Calls himself an archeologist.
- What's your name?
- Charles, I work for him.
- Doing what?
- Oh bits of this and bits of that.
Cleaning up the things he finds.
- What things?
- You like to see them then?
- Yeah, sure.
- [Mike] You know, he looks
like a chimp that's dressed up.
- [Mike] Hey look over there,
it's an ancient Celtic waffle iron.
- [Servo] Cool.
- [Crow] Um kid, how does this huge room
fit into this tiny little hut?
- Well what do you know?
- Not much, you?
- [Voiceover] That's been under the sea
for a thousand years they say.
- Viking looks like.
- Yeah?
- That's it.
It was a great sea battle
right off bay here.
- [Servo] Great.
- They throwed them off
and sunk their ships.
- What's that?
- [Servo] Oh that's a taco
gaith bovine growth hormone.
- That's Olgra, the sea spirit.
Just blind like he did that day.
- Sounds like Saint
Patrick and the snakes.
- What are you doing here?
You get out.
- [Mike] Samuel Beckett.
- [Servo] Not cool.
- I'm Joe Ryan.
That's my partner, Sam Slade.
- Hi.
- McCartin's the name.
Wesley aren't ya?
- Yeah.
- I thought so.
Did the boy tell you about all this?
- Yeah a little.
- This stuff has no real value.
Except the to our snake head.
But since I turned up,
no ships area allowed at that island
for more than 24 hours without a permit.
- But friend, we're not sea worthy.
We won't be for three or four days.
- I don't make the orders,
that's the way it is.
- Anyway, we're afloat.
Come on Sam.
- [Crow] We'll go find
a better harbor master.
- Hey how about fresh water?
- We'll give you that.
- Thanks.
- No hard feelings now.
- Oh no.
- [Mike] No wait, you guys
I think there might be.
Please let's talk this out.
- You believe him,
about this permit?
- No.
- Well something's eating him.
- [Servo] You mean besides the lice?
- I wonder what.
- I don't know.
Come on.
Maybe we'll swing a little more weight
around here if we find out.
- [Crow] Let's get some
boiled cabbage first.
- [Mike] Ah, it's the
yearly silky clubbin'.
- Hey Joe look.
- [Servo] He's doing a sailor
and he's still pointing out boats.
- Smack her off Harry.
- [Crow] Beg your pardon.
- [Mike] Oh we're a terrible crew team.
- Are you having any luck?
(indiscernible)
- You know Joe, they can talk english
every bit as good as you and I can.
They just don't want to, that's all.
- You try Harry.
(speaking in foreign language)
- He said there's no time
for talking with strangers.
And the carton does all
the talkin' on the island.
- [Servo] He said, blow
it out your something
I'm not sure.
Joe Strummer goes fishing.
(speaking foreign language)
- Two of the divers didn't come up Joe.
They think they're gone.
- Gone?
- [Crow] Yeah it's a word
meaning not here anymore.
- [Mike] Stop shaking
the boat I'm gonna puke.
(Servo speaking in a foreign language)
(laughter)
- There's one.
(foreign language)
- [Crow] He's got two time
release caplets lets on his back.
- [Servo] Now he's only got one.
- [Mike] Overcome by an
excess of potatoes, Guinness,
and guilt.
- [Servo] Okay let's
take a look at that butt.
- So that's what's worrying McCartin.
- [Mike] I should visit
Taneil when I'm ashore.
- [Servo] The mackerels in the--
- He's dead.
- Dead huh?
- [Crow] How dead?
Well just dead.
- You saw him come up.
You ask me he died of fright.
- [Servo] Couldn't be the boiled back fat
he ate everyday of his life.
- [Mike] I think that's our ship.
It's just they all look the same.
- This is crazy.
- [Servo] Us marrying.
- There was a man lost down there today.
Not even a trace.
Another one saw something
that scared him to death.
- Look Sam, you don't want to go?
Don't go.
- I'm going alright.
Just to make sure you get back to shore.
- [Crow] Oh I got back.
- Sure, with a hat full of gold.
- [Mike] Ha, you get it.
- That's that.
- Yeah okay.
- [Servo] How do these things work?
- [Crow] This one smells like yours.
- [Mike] It's a boat made
of footlong hot dogs.
- [Crow] I'm just gonna hang
it out over the side here.
Don't look.
- [Servo] Thunder boar.
- [Crow] Voyage to the bottom of the yawn.
- [Servo] The abysmal.
- [Crow] Driving Miss Dummy.
- [Mike] Wait, that
doesn't really work at all.
- [Crow] Really.
- [Mike] No really fails
on a whole lot of levels.
- [Crow] Well I try Mike, alright.
- [Mike] Sorry.
- [Servo] Watch for sharks, I accidently
bathed in fish blood this morning.
Did you say?
- [Crow] Wow all this hard water.
Ireland needs the Culligan Man.
- [Mike] Counting plankton is really hard.
- [Servo] Somebody sunk
a Macy's Thanksgiving Day
parade balloon.
- [Mike] Come on, let's get
some stale bread and feed it.
- [Crow] You know what's great though Sam?
I'm wetting my pants in terror
but it really doesn't matter down here.
- What did you see Sam?
- [Servo] Wanna borrow my old dish towel?
- I don't know.
But whatever it was I
never wanna see it again.
- [Mike] Oh like your this big prize.
♫ Show me the way to go home
♫ Ireland ♫
- [Servo] THere's a dead
hobbit in that thing.
- How goes it Sam?
- These are the last few
barrels coming on board now.
- [Mike] Well clear the stage
for a campy musical review.
- Keep back here boy.
- Captain wants to see ya.
- [Crow] Thought his name was McBox.
(speaking Gaelic)
(monkey noises)
- Look kid, get down off there will ya.
- A science experiment.
- What about the permit?
- It's heathen lie.
- Maybe we better see what
this joker's got in mind.
Where is he?
- Come on then.
- [Servo] Well here's the script.
You take my part in the movie for a while.
- [Mike] Their Polynesian torch ceremony
isn't too successful this year.
- What's going on here?
- They think a shark
got the man who is lost.
♫ I will call you ♫
- Mister McCartin I hear you got a beef.
- You were snoopin' around out there.
My diver's told me.
- Yeah and I suppose they told you
to give us all that jazz about a permit.
- Are you doubting my word?
- You're right Mister McCartin I am.
- [Crow] Look, I'm trying
to write Crap's last tape.
- [Mike] May your corn
beef not pickle correctly.
- After your loaded with water, you leave.
Tonight.
- The sooner the better.
- [Servo] The tighter the sweater.
The boys depend on us.
- [Crow] Yay.
There's like one cod left
in the North Atlantic,
but dammit they're gonna get it.
(speaking Gaelic)
- [Servo] No, it's just
grandma taking a swim.
Don't!
- [Crow] Oh, ow.
- [Mike] Patty cake, patty cake.
- [Crow] Hey go check that out kid.
- Father.
- [Mike] How are ya?
- [Servo] It's the rare
isosceles underwater dragon.
- [Crow] Really gentlemen,
must we do this every night?
- [Mike] Aw, poor Robert
Shaw, eaten again.
♫ To each ♫
- Oh hello, I'm Diana Ring.
Inspired by the guy in today's movie
who looks kind of like Samuel Beckett.
We present to you a
tragic comedy in one act.
Waiting for Gorgo.
Thank you, won't we?
- Nothing to be done.
- I'm beginning to come
around to that opinion.
- Let's go.
- We can't
- Why not?
- We're waiting for Gorgo.
- Ah, yes.
(growling)
- And there he is.
(yelling)
- No no no no.
(growling)
(clapping and cheering)
- Thank you.
- Oh no no please.
- Oh my.
- Well be back after this message
for whiskey and cigarettes.
- [Servo] Oh that was fun.
- [Crow] Whiskey and cigarettes.
- [Mike] Look at this.
Poor Irish, ya know, if they're
not invaded by Cromwell,
or infested with leprauchuns,
they got this guy.
- [Servo] I'll get me slingshot.
- Shoot.
♫ Shuffle off to the fellow ♫
- [Mike] McRoar, O'Growl.
- [Servo] Sorry, I'm a little lost.
Can you tell me how to get to Tokyo?
- [Mike] Quick let's emigrate.
- [Servo] This guys good at
pushing kids around, ya know.
(roaring)
- [Mike] Mmm habenero sauce.
- [Crow] Not a very good juggling act.
- [Mike] A real shame for the island.
The let's go Europe people
are visiting tonight.
- [Servo] These walking
catfish are really big, woo.
- [Crow] Dave Folley.
- [Servo] Come on, I was
just coming to the kallie.
I guess you don't want me then.
- [Mike] I'll put on my asbestos underwear
and I'll be back.
- [Crow] Fine I'll spend
my Euros elsewhere.
- [Mike] Well I never.
- [Servo] Open the pub,
come on it's nine a.m.
- [Crow] We all hated End Game.
- Now there's a man looks
like he's got a real problem.
- Uh huh.
Paints with a nose if we
could solve it for him.
- [Mike] I said we're
all out of Lucky Charms.
- Hey hey mister.
We'll be wanting a passage on your ship
just as soon as he gives.
(indiscernible crowd chatter)
- Now hold on.
You'll get your pay if you like.
But there'll be no taking
a passage on any ship.
- Why not?
(crowd agreeing)
- [Crow] I think they're
mumbling a very good point there.
- Now for god's sake let's
go inside and talk about it.
- Sure.
- [Servo] He could be a
Baldwin brother, couldn't he?
- If they all leave now,
my portmen, my divers, the lot of them,
then the whole thing will go to smash.
- Hey I kind of see there point.
- Got any other reason for
not wanting them to leave?
- What do you mean?
- Oh like, uh, maybe they talk to much.
- [Mike] About these laundry tokens.
- Where did you get those?
- Same place as you.
Supposing we got rid of that thing for ya.
- The beast.
- [Crow] That's right, Ian Paisley.
- Do you think you can?
- Maybe.
- [Servo] If you give me one
of your non-sexual massages.
- Let's take another
look in there fast, huh?
- [Mike] I wanna play with
your Hot Wheels again.
- [Servo] Sorry about how this looks
the walls need to be re-dunged.
- Open the safe.
- [Crow] Man I'm the harbor master.
I don't have to listen to you guys.
I can go master the harbor anytime I want.
This is so bogus.
- [Voiceover] You've done
alright for yourself.
- [Servo] Eva.
- How about this for a down payment?
Do you like this one Sam?
- You must be out of your mind.
A thing like that is priceless.
- [Mike] It belonged
to Hagar the horrible.
- And how do you think
you're gonna dispose of it?
- You must've figured out a way.
I bet we can.
(yelling)
You're not getting off easy friend.
Could've grabbed the lot.
- When will you start?
- Now.
Why not?
- [Mike] Heh, totally toasted
your Irish soda bread.
- Mister Ryan.
- [Servo] How's your hope?
- [Servo] And your daughter?
- What is it kid?
- You'll be trying to catch him, Gorgo.
- Yeah, maybe.
Not afraid are ya.
- No, but it's a bad thing you're doing.
A terrible bad thing Mister Ryan.
- Why don't you call me Joe?
- Okay, Joe.
- Okay, Shawn.
- [Servo] But you missed my point,
despite our new familiarity with names.
- Might be able to catch him in the nets.
- [Crow] Who the kid?
- Yeah.
- How do you suppose to
kill a thing like that?
- Oh I don't know.
Dynamite maybe.
- Ever stop to think
what a thing like that
might be worth alive?
- [Servo] Probably buy a
hundred roll neck sweaters.
- [Mike] Bought it from the government.
It's called fatman or something.
- You really think you'll
catch him with that?
- Sure why not?
I think it will a light
selector sort of lure.
If that doesn't work,
we'll try something else.
Okay Harry, come on, okay.
- [Servo] Try something else, brilliant.
(chuckles)
- Johnny stop.
- [Crow] There's a skeleton of
a little French guy in here.
- Ready when you are Joe.
- Okay.
Take her up.
- [Servo] Wait wait,
what are you doing to me?
- Take her out, out.
Lower away.
Down.
- [Mike] Cast him over by those lily pads.
- [Crow] Well I'd sure hate to
go underwater in this thing.
Guys?
- [Servo] He immediately crossed lines
with the guy trying to catch Godzilla.
- [Mike] Let's roll down the window here.
- Uh Tom.
- [Crow] Can I come up now?
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah I can hear yah.
- Give me about 15 fathoms.
- Down.
- [Servo] Would you let me finish?
- [Mike] Yeah, civil war
submarine technology.
- [Servo] Why does that
octopus have a hack saw?
- Tom.
- [Crow] I mean it, I'm really scared now.
- 10 fathoms, how's that?
- Okay, that'll do.
Give me four to five knots.
And try to head down the bay.
- Slow engine.
- [Mike] Shark.
Shark.
- [Servo] A little mood lighting.
- [Crow] Oh if they don't
let me up to go soon,
it will be a yellow submarine.
- [Servo] They drag him into a rock,
'cause they're so
delighted with the red sky.
- [Mike] Steven Segal.
- [Servo] Uuh.
- Tom can you hear me?
Stop the engines.
- Stop engines.
- [Crow] Mmm, canned guy.
- 10 fathoms, not to fast.
I don't want to lose him.
- [Servo] What your laundry sees.
- [Mike] Uh did we develop a step two yet?
- Tom.
Tom, pull up.
- Quick, quick, pull up.
Pull up, up.
- [Crow] Gee yo-man pushy pants.
- Tom, Tom, pull up.
- Pull up.
- [Mike] Rrrr.
Mmm, yummy.
- Tom. Tom.
- [Mike] Rrrr.
Tom, quick.
- Tom pull out.
It won't take anymore,
she'll snap the cable.
Drop the nets!
- Drop the nets.
All hands on deck.
- [Crow] Hey there's no pop top.
- [Voiceover] Drop it.
- [Mike] Now he's laying his eggs.
He must expect me to swim over him.
- [Crow] So did Gorgo coroporate
and just throw himself in the net?
(chuckles)
- [Mike] How did this happen?
- [Servo] Dumb.
- [Voiceover] Heavy on the winds.
- [Mike] Light on the starch.
- [Crow] Easy on the mayonnaise.
- [Servo] We need to have
a big Gorgo bowl tonight.
- [Mike] Wow.
- Bring her in.
- Lower away.
- [Voiceover] Tighten up those nets.
- [Mike] Brian just fell
into one of his pores.
- [Servo] Aah.
- [Crow] Am in Ireland, send real food.
- [Servo] Hello Mister and Miss Umbrian
and all the ships at sea.
- The headlines of the entire world
are being monopolized by
the news of the capture
of a fantastic monster.
Mainly of prehistoric origin,
off the coast of Ireland.
Puzzled scientists are already spectating
that the monster may have been released
from some vast oceanic cavern,
far beneath the earth's crust.
By unprecedented volcanic eruption
which occurred in the area last week.
Some scientific authorities are suggesting
the whole thing is merely
an elaborate Irish hoax.
Nevertheless, the Irish
government is sending
two of it's top paleontologists
to claim the creature for Ireland.
If it does exist.
- [Crow] Oh they set up the phone
so he can talk to his family.
- [Mike] Hi honey, got
captured again, yeah.
- There's your friend professor.
- I'll tell my partner your here.
Radio skipper.
- [Crow] London turtle neck company
has issued a recall of
potentially fatal flaw.
Oh great.
- Those two professors from
Dublin just come on board.
- Show 'em up.
- [Servo] I gotta go,
no honey, I'm fine.
I gotta go, there's some guys.
- I wonder if you realize Captain Randy
the enormous scientific
value of this discovery.
- I think we do professor.
- Well then, I shall wire
this to University of Dublin
- In order to make preparations
to receive the animal.
You will proceed to Dublin.
- [Mike] Uh, who jiffed?
- Where you'll be properly
compensated for your services.
- Oh sure sure.
- Well, we'll meet there.
Unless you would like
one of us to go with you.
- Oh that won't be necessary professor.
- [Crow] We won't eat much.
- There was one thing.
The animal's skin should be kept wet
in a continuous stream of water.
- I see.
- This is most important.
- I'll take care of it.
- When do you intend sailing Captain?
- Tonight, if that's okay by you.
- Sooner the better.
See you in Dublin.
- University of Dublin.
Properly compensated.
- [Servo] Sentence fragments.
- Big deal.
- Take a look at this Sam.
- [Servo] Take a look at this Sam.
- From Jalk and Sax in London.
They offer 30,000 against
50 percent of the gross.
- [Crow] 50 percent of Mary Gross I mean.
- Set a course for London Sam.
- [Servo] I got a
hankerin' for organ meat.
- [Mike] Forgot to bring in the stringer.
Gorgo's draggin'.
- [Crow] Soon Gorgo's
scampering around the deck,
making friends with all the sailors.
- [Servo] Oh grace.
- [Mike] Whoa that was me, sorry.
Whoops.
- [Crow] Ah kid, could you salt yourself
and come over here?
- I came to let you go back to the sea.
- [Crow] Or maybe lay in some marinade.
- [Mike] I think Gorgo just needs
some new points and plugs.
- [Crow] Go play on Gamra's back kid,
I'm not into it.
- You little knot head.
What do you think you're doing?
- Take it easy.
- I came to let him go back to the sea
where he belongs.
- Why?
- Maybe to save their silly skins from ya.
- I got a good notion to
toss you over the side.
- You wouldn't be sending me back now.
- Harry.
- [Voiceover] Here.
- Better get our little
stow away into a bunk.
And wash his face.
Hey, put a guard on that thing 24 hours
and give him my rifle.
- [Crow] Don't give the monster a rifle.
- I could be watching
him for you, ya know.
You'd be great, wouldn't ya?
- Now if it so much as
moves, start shooting
and then run like the devil.
- [Mike] Pick up my tail
and clatter across the deck
with my cloven hooves?
Alright.
- [Servo] Hey, screw, reach in my pocket
and grab me a cigarette.
- Tell us something kid.
Has anyone ever seen that thing before?
- [Mike] Randall B. did, but he was drunk.
- Nobody had to see
it, to know it's there.
- [Crow] Is this kid
speaking in Bam-bam language?
- Go back to sleep kid.
- [Mike] We'll be turning
you over at Interpol.
Goodnight.
- [Crow] Let's go swipe
the Captain's strawberries.
That's always fun, eh?
♫ Average sized bubbles in the brine ♫
- Just phosphorus Sam.
But it's coming from the scuffers.
- It's the water off the animal.
- So it's still salt water.
You seen spirits too?
(screaming)
- [Servo] Someone didn't
rinse out the sink
after he shaved.
- Crew.
Decks quick.
- [Crow] Gorgo seduced the guard
and then tried to kill him.
- Come on.
- [Servo] I was having an
anti scurvy lime but fine.
- [Mike] Oh no, it's the cute one, doh.
- Get him ready for bail Sam.
Kid I told you to stay below.
- [Crow] Okay, I'll go
up and stay below then.
- [Servo] Hot head.
- Filled with butter?
- Guys look at this.
Look what I got.
The William Slyvester
version of Trivia Pursuit.
- William Slyvester, hmmm?
- Yeah, yeah, I was going to
get the baby boomer version
of the William Sylvester
version of Trivia Pursuit.
But I just thought the basic version,
you know, would be a lot more fun.
What color do you want?
- Well let me answer
that Mike by asking you
who the hell is William Sylvester?
- Come on, he's the guy in today's movie.
- I'm not recalling any
guy in today's movie.
- Oh come on, he was the
main guy in today's movie.
Plus he was in Riding with Death,
and Devil Doll, plus 2001 Space Odyssey.
- Plus a whole bunch of other.
Oh, oh I see what you guy's are doing.
I see, you're trying to learn all about
William Sylvester, so you can beat me
at the William Sylvester
version of Trivia Pursuit.
Well it ain't gonna happen.
You can go first though Crow.
- I don't want to.
- Here you go.
Okay, you have history
of William Sylvester.
Okay, oh, oh man, this is so easy.
In 2001 A Space Odessey, what character
did William Sylvester play?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean you don't?
Haywood Floyd, Haywood Floyd.
Everybody knows.
- Haywood Floyd.
- Okay fine your turn Servo.
- Oh goody.
Okay here we go.
- Oh man, this is incredible.
In the movie Gorgo, who
played the character of Sam?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean?
It was William Sylvester.
It was William--
We're watching the movie today.
Come on you guys.
You're not even trying.
It's like your trying to sabotage
my William Sylvester
version of Trivia Pursuit.
- We are Mike.
- We patently don't care
about William Sylvester.
- Not a bit.
- So your conceding.
- Yes, we conceed.
- Yes yes yes yes
I know more about William
Sylvester than you do.
Or you.
Yes yes yes.
(beeping)
Woo hoo hoo, oh movie time.
- [Mike] Yes, yes.
- [Servo] Your own game.
- [Mike] Woo.
- [Servo] And Buddy Hackett on trumpet.
- Down, down.
Let her clear.
Keep her clear.
- [Crow] Men not without hats.
- [Voiceover] Lower it a bit.
- Unique in evolutionary biology
and you turn it into a circus freak.
Outrageous.
Quite apart from the
fact that you stole it.
- [Mike] Dorkin.
- Now that's a matter of opinion.
- What's this all about?
- We know absolutely
nothing about this animal.
It's extremely dangerous.
- We've managed to
handle it alright so far.
- [Servo] One guy died, but.
- They carry disease bearing
parasites and bacteria.
- [Corw] Like me.
- And you move him into
the heart of a great city.
- Look, what do you want?
- First the opportunity
to make a complete study.
- Okay.
If it doesn't interfere with business.
- Believe me gentlemen,
once the animal is in store and accounct
you'll be given every facility.
- I presume you've thought of
the need of giving the animal
a trangquilling drug
before you transport it.
'Cause if you haven't, you better.
- Well, they bet on then.
- Good day.
- [Servo] Which one of
these guys is Dorkin?
It's hard to tell from this picture.
- [Mike] Yes Dorkin means
great entertainment.
- [Crow] Dorkin under the big top.
Come see the delifghtful Dorkin midgets
and the funny Dorkin clowns.
- [Voiceover] In our most
unusaul telecast to date.
We bring you the arrival of Gorgo.
This creature which should of been extinct
10,000,000 years ago, is
truly an awesome site.
As it is transported thought
he streets of modern London.
On it's way to Battersea Park.
Of course, funderers are
notoriously sckeptical.
And a good many we spoken too
(loud mumbling)
But this animal is real.
Take my word for it.
- [Mike] I'm Dennis Thatcher.
So please keep off any
unauthorized traffic
along the route, as a
precautionary measure.
Although we're assured there's no danger.
The creature has been given
massive amounts of tranquilizer.
Much closer to this thing,
and I could do with a bit
of tranquilizer myself.
Actually it's no joke.
- [Crow] I need drugs.
- [Voiceover] There are rumors
that the animal has killed
a number of persons already,
in the process of it's capture.
- [Servo] But they were
all Irish so it's okay.
- [Voiceover] Now we can
see the circus crowds
at Battersea Park in the festival gardens.
Wehre Gorgo, as he is called,
we dont' know why, will be
exhibited to the public.
- [Mike] And Hitler pulls up.
- Here we can see the
intrepid Captain Ryan.
The one with the cap,
getting out of the car
with his partner Mister Slade.
- [Crow] Flinstone.
- There's the man who captured the animal.
And I don't envy them the job.
And our own Mister Dorkin,
of Dorkin's Circus and the checkered suit.
- [Crow] In the chicken suit?
- [Mike] That I don't see.
- [Voiceover] And by the
way, we'll be interviewing
the Mister Dorkin shortly
at Battersea Park.
So stay with us.
And of course ladies and gentlemen.
I realized at once, that this was the most
shattering discovery of the 20th century.
And so I contracted the
exhibition of the animal.
We've built a special enclosure,
you'll see it later on.
We rushed the job through,
just so everyone in London
would have the opportunity
of seeing Gorgo, themselves.
- I have a report from Dublin
that the Irish government
are going to take legal
proceedings to recover the animal.
- Yes, I believe that's the truth.
Of course the matter will
have to go through the courts
in the usual way.
And since I have no way of knowing
how quickly they'll reach that decision,
I suggest anyone who wants to see Gorgo,
do so at Battersea Park.
- That name Gorgo.
Does it have any special significance?
- Yes sir, of course, the
monster of Greek mythology.
The Gorgons.
A creature so terrifying it
would turn a man to stone.
- [Mike] This is for Dorkin.
- How much money do you
expect to make out of it.
- I'll answer that question later on.
- [Crow] Don't bother
the man, he's Dorkin.
- [Servo] We have to clean up
after Mighty Joe Young first.
- Lower away.
Easy.
- Okay Tom.
- Easy does it.
- [Crow] One day at a time.
Be in the moment.
Don't sweat the small stuff.
- [Servo] That's digging into my groin,
if you could just...
- [Voiceover] Fore.
- [Mike] Playing through.
- Tranquilizer seems to be working.
- [Crow] I'm very mellow.
- So far.
- [Servo] Is there a union
for monster wrangler's here?
- [Mike] Wanna help Joe?
- [Crow] They're trying to
exhume William Howard Taft.
- [Voiceover] Wire cutters.
- Wire cutters, quick.
- Okay.
- Cut the net.
- [Servo] He has a splinter,
let's take care of that first.
- [Mike] Mmm, world's biggest porchetta.
- [Crow] Look we all know
where this is heading.
Can we just start tossing Brits around?
- [Servo] Mister Gorgo, is
it true you had an affair
with Judith Asner?
- That's a hell of a dumb thing to do.
- [Servo] I'm up, I'm up.
- [Crow] Yeah, I've got net hair.
♫ I crush you
♫ You get crushed ♫
- [Mike] This is like
England's 178th finest hour.
- [Servo] Help us, help.
- [Mike] The Japanese that
lies dormant in all of us
comes alive in situations like these.
- Over here.
- [Crow] Sit.
You sit.
- [Mike] Hey, best teeth in England.
- [Servo] Free Huey.
- Tranquilizers.
- [Crow] This is truly a black day
in the history of Dorkin.
- [Mike] Will this stop England's Dorkin?
- [Servo] He looks like a chocolate bunny.
- [Mike] Aw, looks like Crow.
- [Crow] Ooh, I didn't know
elephants exploded on impact.
- [Servo] Wow.
- Come on lead the way.
- We'll take the other side.
- [Mike] We've installed this system
rather than the traditional
hand towels Gorgo.
It prevents chapping
and spread of disease.
- [Servo] I left instructions with Mothra.
If I don't come back, he's
gonna wreck this joint.
- Give him another blast.
- [Crow] Embarass him.
Ask him about the size of his brain.
- [Servo] Look, can I just eat Manchester?
- [Crow] Ho, right in the store.
- Wow.
- [Mike] Quit draggin'
tail Gorgo, come on.
Poor guy was just there for
take your brother to work day.
- [Servo] Gorgo gave
himself a little time out.
- [Crow] Buses really run
frequently here in London.
- [Mike] Come see Gorgo,
he'll kill your family.
Come, get killed by Gorgo.
- [Crow] Dorkin with
John Collins' big dipper.
Happy couples enjoying
Dorkin all night long.
- [Mike] Hey, it is balloons.
Insulation on a stick.
- [Voiceover] Everyone in the
world is talking about Gorgo,
but only you can see him.
And only here at Dorkins.
Two lanes, both sides, 5
shillings ladies and gentlemen.
Bring the children, very instructive.
This way.
Hurry, hurry, hurry to see Gorgo.
The last remaining link
with prehistoric times.
Only 5 shillings ladies and gentlemen.
- [Crow] Hooray for Dorkin.
- There a still a few remaining places.
Two lanes, both sides.
Bring the children, very instructive.
What's that madam,
looks like your husband?
Go inside to find out.
65 foot Gorgo and heavier
than six elephants.
- [Servo] Oh that this tu-tu solid flesh
would belt thaw and
ease it's self into ado.
- [Crow] It's reject day at the circus.
- [Voiceover] Ice cream
here, get your ice cream.
♫ Mister Bojangles ♫
- Peanuts, popcorn.
- [Servo] Hey, John Quincy Adams.
- Get your peanuts here.
♫ It's not unusual ♫
- [Crow] Thank you.
(crowd chatter)
- [Mike] Mmm, brain matter.
- [Servo] Hi there cutie, heh heh.
- [Crow] Hey ladies, I know Gorgo.
Wanna meet him?
- Looks like a full house.
- Not bad.
- [Mike] That's why I'm dorkin.
♫ Don't break my heart,
achy breaky heart ♫
- [Crow] Great, Colonel Tom
Parker's gonna manage Gorgo.
- [Servo] Next show in
half an hour Mister Gorgo.
- Hi Sam.
I was dropping into town.
Thought you might like to come a long,
have a couple drinks.
- I'm having a couple of drinks.
- [Servo] I'm just tearing
through the pink squirrels.
- How's business?
- [Voiceover] Great, great.
- Why don't you get out of this dump?
Live a little.
I got a suite of rooms at
the best hotel in town.
- [Crow] Gorgo's got the big bed, but.
- This suits us.
- [Mike] Great Gorgo ate another elephant.
- Look Joe, these animals are gone crazy.
Something's gonna happen I can feel it.
Mike's already been killed.
Who's next?
- I'm sorry about Mike as you are.
It's a tough break, that's all.
- Well he's got a wife and two kids.
- Okay, well we'll send her some money.
- But he's dead.
- [Servo] Okay, we'll
send her another husband.
- There's gonna be a lot more tough breaks
before this is over.
- You've been listening to
your new partner too much.
- I've been listening to myself.
(phone rings)
- [Crow] Oh, that'll be me again.
- Hello.
- Yeah, just a moment.
It's the professor.
Says they've been trying to find ya.
- [Servo] Do you know where you are?
- This time of night?
Hello, yeah.
- [Crow] I'm smoking, sure, yeah.
- Yeah if you say so.
Okay.
- [Mike] Well, I'm suppose to hit you.
- Spotted something out, you coming along?
- Yeah sure.
- [Crow] Then we'll go
beat up some clowns.
- [Servo] But I don't want
to be Billy and mummy.
- [Mike] I hope money
penny's happy to see me.
- [Crow] Holy worm's busiest day ever.
- Come in gentlemen.
Captain Ryan.
- [Servo] Yes.
- The creature you captured
is not an adult specimen.
- You mean it isn't fully grown?
- No.
In fact we believe it is
in rather early infancy.
- [Servo] We need to change him.
- You trying to say there
may be a fully grown
one of these things around some where?
- It's a fair assumption.
Where there are offspring,
there are generally parents.
- How big would a full grown one be?
- Approximate guess.
- [Mike] According to my
unnecessarily large book.
- [Voiceover] The infant.
- [Crow] The out-fant.
- The adult.
- That would make him
nearly 200 feet tall.
- At the very least.
- Obviously the proper authorities
must be notified at once.
- What are you trying to do?
Stir up an old hornet's nest?
Because of a few calculations
made on a piece of paper?
Nuts to that.
- I'm afraid Captain, the decision
is no longer in your hands.
- [Servo] One two three step.
Two two, no wrong.
Practice, practice.
Two three.
- [Mike] Boy these late
shows nobody ever comes.
- [Crow] Hey kid wanna play me eat you?
- [Servo] What's that?
The pain.
What did I just experience?
Oh yeah, pain.
- [Mike] Ooh he's got
Betty Davis eye real bad.
- [Crow] Yikes.
- [Servo] I held my breath for
a million years, did you see?
- [Mike] Quiet, I'm finishing a monologue
for Billy Whitelaw.
- [Crow] Ow I stubbed my toe on a duplex.
- [Servo] It's the road company of stomp.
- [Mike] I'm the new harbor master.
- [Servo] Aw this feels great.
Oh my aching bogs.
- Admiral Brooks, I realize
the situation is fantastic.
- One expects the fantastic
from your scientists these days.
- [Mike] Stupid squid.
- Tell me Admiral, have you ever seen
the animal that was captured?
- I'm afraid I haven't had the time.
- Then perhaps you should take the time.
- And when you do,
remember it first appeared
at Nada Island.
- Monitor reports there's
been no communication
with Nada Island for three days, sir.
- [Servo] Thank you Timmy.
- Three days.
- [Crow] Oh and pinnafore's
about to start sir.
(beeping and tapping)
- [Voiceover] Her majesty's
air craft carrier, Royal Open.
From the Admiral T. Whitehall.
Proceed to area N34.
And report any unusual
sightings or conditions
in the vicinity of Nada Island.
This is priority A.
Repeat.
♫ One ♫
- [Crow] Meanwhile bits of
the empire are falling away
so long India, goodbye Rhodesia.
- [Mike] Talmud, Talmud, oh wait.
I mean, Torah, Torah.
- [Crow] Leave me alone, get away from me.
- [Mike] The SS Curly has arrived.
- [Crow] Hmm, there's a spot on my window.
- [Mike] I'm drawing Binky.
- Reconnaissance to corvette.
Alter course to 310.
Repeat.
Course 310.
- Right.
They spotted something sir.
- Port four points.
Port four points.
- Aye-aye.
- [Crow] Going over our own weight.
It's fun.
- [Mike] Deploy pitching machine.
- [Servo] The order comes in.
Kill Willy.
- [Crow] She has perm rods in her hair.
- [Mike] Man I love krill.
- Fire number one Terry.
- [Servo] Wait wait, we can't
all be number one turret.
- [Mike] Look at this.
Doorman just roam the streets of London
looking for people to serve.
- [Servo] I will not fake distress calls.
I will not fake distress calls
- Admiral Brooks.
- [Crow] We decided
England is shaped funny.
- Gentlemen, you've
been asked to come here
to supply us with any information
that might be helpful.
Nada Island has been destroyed.
Reconnaissance aircraft
has sighted the creature
in this area here.
- If you ask me sir, that looks as though
the thing's heading for England.
- Quite.
The majesty herself
called for an explanation.
Do you have one?
- Well, we were draining
a stream of water on it
during the passage.
It was professor Flahherty's instructions.
Maybe he left some sort of track.
- I see.
- [Mike] Way to go.
- Is that possible?
- Yes, it's possible.
- Royal Oak for Admiral Brooks please.
Royal Oak coming in for Admiral Brooks.
- Good.
They've reported at least two direct hits.
- You killed it?
- It's disappeared beneath the sea.
They saturated the area
with death charges.
No living thing could escape.
It's certainly been killed.
- [Servo] We killed it Moe.
- [Mike] A giant sea camel.
- [Servo] Ah, pork fed grits.
- [Mike] There's got to
be a morning after sir.
- Capsized.
- [Crow] I've got to have my cap sized.
- With every man aboard.
- This is terrible.
- [Mike] I see it as an opportunity.
- Well alright, now what?
- What would you do?
- Turn that thing at the
festival gardens loose,
what else?
Take it back to the sea, while
we still have the chance.
- What the hell's a matter with you?
This is the 20th century.
There must be someway of
handling an over grown animal.
- There's no doubt that
we can stop the creature.
- [Servo] Yes.
- We'll call you if we need you again.
Good evening gentlemen.
- [ Crow] Ah but could
you postpone your plans
plans to bring the 500 foot stick insect
into the middle of London?
- [Servo] Dorkin just
doesn't seem that same now.
- [Mike] Nope.
Good night Gorgo.
- [Servo] The clowns
let me borrow their car.
It's great.
- [Mike] Well I do live in a trailer.
Thought I'd listen to some Bob Seger
and watch some Nascar.
- No, he'll kill you.
- I'm turning him loose.
- Stop it Sam.
He'll kill you.
- Letting him go.
- [Crow] Don't vomit on me again.
- [Servo] Don't fuss so over me, please.
- [Mike] Fem-punch.
- Stop it Sam, you're crazy.
- [Crow] Ooh I like punching you.
- [Servo] We're going to the vet, right?
- Sam.
Hey you alright?
Sam.
Are you alright?
- [Servo] You mad the pants too long.
- [Shawn] Sam.
- Go on kid.
♫ Failed Britainia
♫ You never ruled the waves ♫
- [Mike] Ah here.
- [Crow] Well we've taken out the QE2,
the Bismark, and the Loveboat,
but we missed Gorgo.
- [Servo] Look what the
neighbors are doing.
- Reconnaissance to corvette.
Observation negative.
Repeat negative.
- [Mike] Can I get some help here?
There's usually a guy with a thing.
- Fighting with all hands,
the Admiral's team has deployed
major forces of the naval reef.
Off the mouth of the Estring.
In an attempt to locate
and destroy the monster
even before it reaches
the coastal defenses.
- [Crow] They're firing geese at them.
- [Mike] L, L, L.
L, L, L.
- [Crow] R R R, R R R R.
- [Servo] Man they must get everything.
- Still tracking west 25.
- Roger task force.
Search 20 degrees west.
- [Mike] Ma.
- [Crow] Oh he's so cute.
- [Servo] Is Roger looking at me?
- [Mike] Look at those
two, it's disgusting.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
- [Crow] You know at this point
I'd be happy to see Cher
straddling these guns.
- [Servo] Isn't this
cutting into the Navy's
groping and harassment time?
- [Mike] The English reject
beer that's too cold.
- [Crow] This is the equivalent
of the Navy getting drunk
and throwing cherry bombs over board.
- [Servo] Ten whales are dead sir.
- [Mike] Um, we are a submarine right?
Good.
- [Crow] Ooh, ooh, I think
I just saw Larry Hovas.
- [Voiceover] That's the cue sir.
- [Servo] Oops, we left the
cap in the accounting tower.
- Steady as she goes for torpedo check.
Holes two, seven, five.
Range 1500.
- [Voiceover] Holes two, seven, five, sir.
Firing yet.
- Ready to open fire sir.
- Tile one.
- [Mike] Moving much longer than it
would've been without us sir.
- Fire two.
- [Crow] Can't talk now, bye.
- Attacking target in search area.
- [Servo] I need a bigger monitor.
- Contact broken.
Target moving toward the estery.
Too fast to follow.
- Getting submarine control.
Sector 28.
- We're just closing the last
of the submarine nets now sir.
- [Mike] Mm-hmm.
This must keep foul
balls out of the ocean.
- [Servo] Cigarette alert.
Everybody smoke.
- Yes.
Oh no, the nets are being torn.
And the connection is gone.
- [Crow] I just got red contacts.
What do ya think?
- [Mike] Wow, lieutenant modest
crotch on the right here.
- Nothing further you can do now.
- [Servo] Well they've
forgotten your Moo Goo Gai Pan.
- The creatures got through.
Smash the nets.
Get me river patrol.
- [Servo] Uh-oh.
- [Crow] Hey hey hey, it's Fat Albert.
- [Mike] Now is this the mom or the dad?
- [Servo] I don't know.
How do you sex one of these things?
- [Crow] Well you put the lights down low,
you put on a little Barry White.
- [Servo] That's not what I mean.
- [Servo] That's ridiculous.
- [Mike] Let's get out.
- [Voiceover] You can see the
huge beast still advancing.
Second line of defense has been organized.
Greatly reinforced.
- Oh hey what's this?
- Looks like the nanites made
them self a little circus.
- They must've been watching the movie,
the little dickenses.
- Well, let's see.
Hello nanites, what's going on down there?
- Ladies and gentlemen,
children of all ages,
come to the spectacular,
gargantuan, nanite
protos and darkened combined,
avaonic circus and carnival of soul.
- With Nate the clown.
- Marvel at the spectacle
of wild subcelluar animals.
- Nate the Clown.
- Thrill at the daring
of the Nanitino family
as they fly a full 15
mic-grounds about center ring.
- And Nate the Clown.
- Whoa, it sounds great.
How much does it cost.
- I'm not done yet.
Gasp in horror at the
largely ironic midway
and squeal with delight at
the antics of Nate the Clown.
- Hey that's me.
(laughs like a clown)
- Okay, okay, you've sold me.
How much?
- Only 25 cents, that's right a quarter.
Two bits, five nickels, one
quarter of a green back.
- Well I've got a handful of quarters.
You guys in?
- You bet.
- I want to see the ironic midway.
- Here ya go, pallie.
(screams)
- Oh horrors, the curse
of the circus is upon us.
Giant stones fall from the sky.
And our clown is dead.
(crying)
- [Voiceover] Ah, the
microbes are on the loose.
The ameobas are on the rampage.
Run!
- Ow, sorry.
I was just tossing one on and
Oh!
- Here comes another.
The circus is destroyed.
(sighs)
- Maybe we should go to the zoo instead.
- That's a good idea.
We'll be right back.
- Clown killer.
- Maybe.
- [Crow] Geez, did ya
see that clown blood?
- Man your stations.
- [Servo] I don't think
the sanctions are working.
- Get your lines ready sir.
- Open the valves.
- [Crow] Ah, they're gonna get
it drunk on woodpecker cider.
♫ Downtown ♫
- [Voiceover] Come on hop to it.
- [Servo] The kales navy
only battle the creature.
- [Crow] Come on it's the 5:15 monster.
- Be ready.
Let's get behind those sandbags.
- [Mike] This feels good,
squishing the mud between my toes.
- Fire.
- [Servo] Got him.
He's dead.
It's over.
- [Mike] Good, let's go.
- [Crow] This is a fine welcome.
They treated Jerry Lee
Lewis better than this.
- [Mike] Bullocks Gorgo.
(laughing)
- [Crow] Now that just
seemed completely avoidable.
- Get me army headquarters.
- Atomic weapons are out of the question.
(mumbling)
- [Servo] Wacko.
- Tanks?
Of course.
- [Mike] Come on let's do something easy
like put down some Arabs or something.
- [Servo] Those things are great.
They're built like Volvos.
- Attention.
This is a special bulletin.
Civil defense authorities have
declared a state of emergency
for all London areas within
three miles of the River Tims.
- [Crow] Ah, he'll
probably be sated on people
from the suburbs by then.
- [Servo] There's a sale on bumber shoots.
- [Crow] See it's not so bad.
Keep your chin up.
Stiff up a lip.
- [Voiceover] The streets
must be kept clear
for military defense personnel.
- [Mike] And good humor trucks.
- [Servo] Ah the queen mama's brought out
to fight the beast.
Hello.
(yelling)
- [Servo] Yes sir.
- [Crow] Being in the British is a sench.
You just hold a rifle,
run around, and look busy.
- [Voiceover] Get off the street.
- [Crow] Okay.
- [Mike] No, no he's talking to guys.
- [Voiceover] Get off the
streets and go to your homes.
- [Mike] Now tanks are brought
in to roll over the doll.
- [Crow] Yeah this is
the same thing they do
when Oliver Reid's in town.
(laughing)
- [Servo] Can't believe
we all missed the bus.
- [Voiceover] Up right there.
Move in, move in.
Take your positions.
Parting positions.
- It's advancing up river
directly towards us.
- [Crow] Stay here and get killed?
Yes sir.
- Very good, sir.
- [Servo] A woman.
- Although the army
indicates full confidence,
they report growing
casualties among their forces.
We are told that Donning Street
is in constant communication
with other world capitals,
but great concern is expressed.
- [Mike] Though I detected
a snicker in their voice.
- Call headquarters.
Shoot the flares.
Open side fire.
Standby.
Commence fire.
- [Crow] Hey, wait I don't have my gun.
- [Mike] You're the ones who
sold me my anti-missile armor.
- [Crow] Ah this is really
cleaning my pores, thank you.
- [Servo] Now Mike, you're
probably gripped with the urge
to say London Bridge is
falling down at this point,
but don't, don't.
This is actually the Tower Bridge.
♫ London Bridge is falling down ♫
- [Servo] Mike what did I just tell you?
- [Mike] What?
Oh right, sorry.
- [Crow] Hi, guys.
- [Mike] Why that's quite bracing
getting knocked off the bridge.
- [Servo] Oh red ants.
- The bridge is gone.
One of London's oldest landmarks
smashed like matchwood.
Nothing can stop this
beast so far, nothing.
Not even point blank canon fire.
- [Servo] Not women.
- The entire bridge?
Then the power of this thing is fantastic.
- [Servo] And I'm on half power as it is.
- [Crow] Hi, I'm Gorgo,
but I'm not Mormo of
the thousand-faced moon.
(laughing)
- [Servo] Maybe Mary Poppins
flies in and kicks his ass.
- [Mike] That I'd pay to see.
No he has the power to superimpose rocks.
- Check the missile units.
Yes sir.
- [Crow] Cliff Richards is
opening up the palladium.
- [Servo] Juggling pins I brought in,
and the monster's managed to keep five
up in the air at once.
- And meanwhile the Russians
slip in the back door,
take over London,
and rename it Khrushchevgrad.
- [Crow] They could fling
really hot curry in his eyes.
- [Servo] Yeah or spray
him with malt vinegar.
- Back, back, come back.
- Yes sir, I will.
40 degrees.
- [Crow] Hey it's large Bob.
- [Mike] It's Big Ben.
- [Crow] Oh sure, Mike.
- [Servo] You think it's noticeable.
- [Mike] Nah.
- [Servo] Oh boy.
- [Crow] Big Ben.
- [Mike] It was running
a little fast anyway.
- [Crow] Got a few people
caught in my teeth.
- Come on.
- [Servo] I want access
to the Law Library.
- Burned out our connection.
- [Mike] Here let's check is air pressure.
Maybe that's the problem.
- Where's Shawn?
- [Crow] Ah, General Shawn.
Glad we found you.
- [Voiceover] Shawn.
Come on.
- [Servo] Come on, we have to
rescue our child that we hate.
- All homes of this area
must be evacuated at once.
- [Mike] The darlings.
You have no time to
remove your belongings.
Get out of the area.
Proceed in a westwardly direction.
- [Crow] Well the good
news is he may crush Sting.
- [Servo] You think so?
- [Mike] Good news for everyone.
- [Servo] A lot of people
will end up in hospital
because of this,
perhaps even people from university.
- [Crow] Oh not her majesty's
certified paper clip works,
purveyors of paper clip tour
majesty court since 1743.
- [Servo] It's the London
landmark Banco Espanol.
- [Mike] Hang on I
gotta change some pesos.
- [Crow] It's a Lulu autograph session.
- Run that way Sam.
We'll meet back at--
- [Mike] Great, about four?
I'll bring some beer.
(screaming)
- [Servo] What, what am I offending?
- [Mike] Maybe he just
hates Georgian architecture.
- [Servo] Maybe.
- [Crow] I hope that's not a mating call.
- [Servo] I'm glad you're
killing mother, Gorgo.
- [Mike] You need to find Elton John
so he can write a song about this.
♫ Goodbye England
♫ You've been crushed by giant lizards ♫
- [Crow] Big Ben.
- [Mike] Hey I'm just looking
for a good hat blocker.
I assume King Edward has
sold of all England's secrets
to Gorgo by now.
- [Servo] Man you are tub, kid.
- [Crow] I won't bury you.
- [Mike] Yes you will.
- [Servo] Come on my car's
gonna get towed, move.
- [Mike] At this point,
he's using the kid as a battering ram.
- [Servo] You know if it were me,
I'd just hang back and
kind of look inconspicuous.
- [Crow] Yeah, duck into a
corner, pull my hat down,
read the paper.
- [Mike] Aren't you glad you used Dial?
- [Servo] This guy panicked
but he stopped the path.
- [Mike] I'm looking
over a four leaf clover.
- [Crow] Stubby Kaye,
Al Lewis, Archie Rice.
- [Servo] Scabbed knees.
(screaming)
- [Mike] I trust event figure
will get me through this.
- [Servo] Insti-flood.
- It's alright Shawn.
We'll be alright.
- [Crow] It's Gorgo sweat.
- [Mike] Hey look, I
don't want to be near you.
Take me back to the soldiers.
- [Servo] By the way, does
this mean no work tomorrow?
- [Crow] Oh man, I floated
an air biscuit back there.
I gotta get away from it.
- Piccadilly, the heart of London.
Words can't describe it.
- [Mike] I'll speak in whole numbers.
- [Voiceover] Not even
the worst of a blitz.
This section is complete shambles.
People running mad with fear.
Fires everywhere.
- [Servo] The fire department
still running over people.
- [Crow] Hello Piccadilly.
First I'm gonna see a Noël
Coward play on the west end.
- [Mike] I'm so proud.
My son's name in lights.
- [Servo] What should I
do with this building?
I'll crush it I guess.
It's what I do best.
Yeah.
- [Mike] People are running
through the streets saying,
this simply isn't done.
You'll be hearing from my solicitor.
- [Servo] He's everywhere.
- There's too much smoke.
- [Crow] Hey kid give
that guy in a wheel chair
a little kick.
He's in our way.
- Piccadilly Circuit.
There's no way of telling where
this thing will turn next.
I don't care how important
it is, you must interrupt.
It's imperative that I speak
to the Minister at once.
- [Servo] But the Minister
nipped out to bingo.
- [Mike] And they sneak
off and bomb the Falklands.
- [Servo] I wish they'd
get back to Dorkin.
- [Crow] Yeah there was a lot of Dorkin
at the beginning of the movie.
They should show that some more.
- [Servo] Sure, I mean who
wouldn't rather watch Dorkin
than this stock footage.
- [Crow] I just really, really
like to watch people Dorkin.
- [Mike] Hey that doesn't even work.
- [Crow] Oh it works Mike.
- [Mike] That's enough you two.
Enough Dorkin.
You know what I mean stop it.
- [Servo] Zinga.
Maybe they could drop
Robbie Coltrane on them.
- [Mike] Yeah how about
the two fat ladies?
- [Servo] Pacifist or not,
Ghandi's gotta be chuckling about now.
- [Crow] Oh let me guess.
The air force is ineffectual.
- [Mike] Bring it on.
It's like eating Pad Thai.
- Repent.
Repent.
- [Servo] Oh no it's well past tea.
- Repent.
Repent.
- [Crow] I'm not wearing any pants.
No pants baby.
- [Servo] Mike, can one repent
if one hasn't yet pented?
- [Mike] I'll get back to you.
- [Servo] Okay.
- I see.
Well let me know the moment you are.
- [Mike] You needed a vaudeville team.
- Thanks for coming.
- It's already heading
for Battersea park, sir.
That's the place to stop.
- How much voltage do
you think may be required
to electrocute this animal?
- 2,000,000 3,000,000 volts?
Just a guess.
There's not much precedent to go on that.
- Get me Battersea Power Station.
- [Servo] You brought the wrong kid.
- Is he okay?
- [Crow] Say hello to
the nice folks, Bobby.
- He'll be alright.
- [Mike] I use turtle
wax to prevent chipping.
- [Servo] Toenail fungus, yikes.
- Switch on.
Full power.
- [Crow] Ah they got the
new pudding master 5000.
♫ If I ruled the world
♫ Everyday day would be
the first day of Spring ♫
- [Mike] Okay drop it.
- [Crow] Man these little
army guys are chewy.
- [Servo] Have to write a foot finish.
- We're waiting at Battersea.
Waiting.
- [Mike] Would you die?
- Praying for a miracle.
The entire electricity
of all industrial London
has been diverted to the wires surrounding
the small animals enclosure.
Will it be enough?
Will it be enough to stop the huge beast?
Will the miracle granted?
Or will it be yet another
of man's puny efforts
to oppose this irresistible
force of ancient nature.
- [Mike] After this
message from cat brain.
- Hey Sam.
- [Servo] You're wearing
the tie I bought you.
- [Crow] How the hell
do you work this thing?
- [Mike] My shield's almost down,
hall breech eminent.
- [Servo] He's heading for the hot tub.
- [Crow] I'm rather put out by all this.
- [Mike] Quit readjusting the sub woofer.
- The power circuit has
just been completed sir.
- What's the reading?
- Full amperage sir.
The lines won't take anymore.
- [Crow] Give me back my son.
- [Mike] I love you Mimsy.
- [Servo] Oh big amperage?
- [Crow] Mom you're embarrassing me.
- [Mike] Our cast in case you've forgot.
- [Servo] Dorkin.
Sorry.
- She's going down.
No, now she's torn the wires.
Now nothing.
- [Mike] I think the editing
philosophy of this movie was
don't stay on anything too long.
It doesn't look good enough.
- [Crow] This is treating
my bipolar disorder.
(laughing)
- [Servo] You're coming
with me, young lizard.
- [Crow] Damn mom, you're big.
- [Mike] Kiss my tail, England.
- We prayed for a miracle.
- [Servo] Now to take its course.
- Maybe our prayers have been answered.
The great city overwhelmed, exhausted.
Lies helpless under the
immeasurable power and ferocity
of this towering apparition
from before the dawn of history.
- [Crow] Why didn't she eat the announcer?
- [Voiceover] Yet as though
disdaining the pygmies
under our feet,
she turns back.
- [Mike] Yeah that's me.
Turns with her young,
leaving the prostrate city.
Leaving the haunts of man,
and leaving man himself
to ponder the proud boasts
that he alone is lord of all creation.
- [Servo] Shut up.
Windbag.
- [Crow] So mom, how's dad?
- [Mike] I ate him.
- [Crow] Oh.
- They're going back now,
back to the sea.
- [Servo] With the blood
of many on her scales.
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] Come on son.
As a treat let's go crush France.
- [Servo] Hurray.
- [Crow] Now the rest of the
story is the Cray brothers
looting London.
- [Servo] This is how My Giant ends.
(humming)
- [Crow] Oh Dorkin was
a person, a character.
Weird.
- [Servo] First naval officer?
There weren't any naval
officers before this movie?
- [Mike] I don't think he was
the first naval officer ever.
- [Servo] No that's precisely
what they're saying.
- [Mike] I don't think that that's it.
- [Crow] Administration.
- [Mike] Dear, dear, dear
what are we gonna do.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa Mike a
little help here please?
- Yeah Mike slight problem here.
- Yeah we went and presold
a series of calendars
featuring the hunks and
babes of the hit film, Gorgo.
- Yeah sold it to a New Jersey firm,
rough looking guys and
dark plate model cars.
- The mob?
- Right the mob.
- The mob.
- The mob, exactly.
Well we filled out our hunk calender
with that William Frawley guy
you seemed to like so much.
- We had no idea there
wouldn't be a single woman
in the whole movie.
- Right now there's the problem.
Save our lives.
- Okay.
Well there are women in the film.
I'm just not sure they have the sizzle
for your mob calender.
- Hell, we'll take what we can get here.
- Alright well Cambot let's have a look
at the monitor there.
If I'm not mistaken,
when the two guys are getting
off the boat in Ireland,
I believe there was a
woman standing right there.
Can we look at that?
- I think you're right.
- Hey.
- Whoa hey yeah.
- Yeah there you go.
I'm not sure she's featured
in the film, however.
- Not a problem.
We airbrush out any blemishes.
Clip her out and put her on
the hood of a Lamborghini,
we got Miss July.
- Right.
- Next.
- Oh okay.
Gorgo's chasing people
through the streets.
Bunch of crowd scenes there.
I think there's a woman there.
Cambot can we fast forward to that?
There.
- Perfect.
Change her hair,
put her in front of a
fireplace at a rugged lodge.
We got a best seller.
- Ka-ching.
- Guys are on your way, okay.
Well back to you Leonard Maltin.
- Why aren't they suffering?
What's the deal, Leo?
- I don't understand it.
In many cases, Gorgo has been known
to induce hallucinations and mild drooling
at the very least.
- Well you better start understanding.
I want the worst movie ever made,
and I want it now, Rex Reed.
- Just hold your water.
Let me see.
I want to hurt them as much as you do.
There's gotta be something really bad,
worst movie.
I would think of something with
Mickey Rourke, wouldn't you?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah now you're talking.
Cross reference that with Eric Roberts,
and we're in business.
You're dead Nelson.
- Yeah I think so.
You know using my new updated
movie and video guide,
we'll find the worst movie ever,
and then it's curtains for you.
- What did you say your name was?
- Maltin, Leonard Maltin.
- I like you Leonard.
(laughing)
(slow music)